Mohsen **Fallahnejad**

Front-End Developer

@ mohsenfallahnjd@gmail.com

17 themohsen.me

Tehran, Iran



A Front-End developer with over 6 years of experience in blending the art of design with programming to deliver engaging user experiences. I create large-scale web applications that work, using JavaScript (Next.js, React, Vue.js), Typescript and CSS (Sass).

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, Next.js, React, Vue.js, Node.js

Tools & Technologies

MongoDB, Git, Vite, Firebase, Postman, Figma, Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

Speax.ai Feb, 2024 - Present

Senior Front-End Developer, Switzerland

- Speax.ai
 - Been part of the product team to work on the Speax front-end app.
 - Implemented the landing page and user dashboard for an AI project, translating design specifications into responsive and interactive interfaces.

Technologies: Next.js, MUI, TypeScript, React Query, next-auth, Zustand, VideoJS, Firebase, reacthook-form.

- Innercircle-Chainmind.com
 - Rebuilt and launched a crypto platform, achieving a 50% improvement in performance and a significant increase in user engagement, now supporting over 500 active users.

Technologies: Next.js, MUI, TypeScript, React Query, next-auth, Redux, react-hook-form, Bun.

Pouya Housh Nov, 2022 - Present

Senior Front-End Developer, Tehran

- Enhanced the Pinorest App by integrating server-side rendering with Next.js, improving SEO metrics by 40% and addressing user feedback for new features.
- Engineered the TehranMoble App by integrating innovative UX features derived from analytics data and customer insights, contributing to the app's dominance with over 80% market share in Tehran.
- · Crafted an official landing page for the company, effectively showcasing corporate identity and side projects.
- Created a Property System Management tool for back-office operations, efficiently managing 300 properties with innovative ticketing and hospitality features, reducing manual processing by 25%.

Technologies: Next.js, TypeScript, MUI, RTKQuery, React Query, Redux, react-hook-form, Bun.

YasnaTeam Jun, 2020 - Sep, 2023

Front-End Developer, Tehran

- Collaborated on developing Quark, a Headless CMS designed for projects ranging from simple blogs to large-scale e-commerce applications.
- Redesigned and modularized the Groot platform using Vue.js, enhancing client experience and reducing build and development time by 50%.
- Developed Jarvis, a local CLI tool for Groot, reducing task completion time by 70% and significantly improving workflow efficiency for the development team.
- Refactored and implemented a comprehensive design system for Groot, incorporating over 40 components to support TypeScript, Sass, and version control
- Architected reusable structures for common website sections, standardizing components and styles for increased customization and efficiency.
- Created SCSS helpers using Sass methods, enhancing global styling efficiency by 50% across projects.
- Packaged components into NPM modules, using Verdaccio, streamlining version management and improving collaboration efficiency for development teams. Reduced deployment times by 70% by providing easy access to updated modules.
- Implemented a Progressive Web Application for IoT connectivity with Raspberry Pi modules, enhancing testing capabilities in refrigerators.
- Built boilerplate with NextJs based on the product team plan.
- Led a front-end team of 5 developers to advance the Quark project, enhancing productivity and code quality in last year.

Technologies: Vue.js, Webpack, Sass, TypeScript, Jest.

Freelance 2017-2019

Web Developer

- Conceptualized and executed a Co-Work Reservation system on WordPress, optimizing booking processes and elevating client experience; resulted in a 40% increase in reservations and a 25% reduction in booking errors.
- Designed and implemented a fully-customized photographer portfolio website that resulted in a 50% increase in client inquiries, showcasing 30+ projects with high-resolution images and optimized user experience for better engagement.

EDUCATION

Guilan University 2016 - 2020

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering

- Organized WeeklyTalk which is a video talking with some people who work as designers, developers or teachers in the tech industry for knowledge-sharing.
- Held a programming marathon inside the University.

ACHIEVEMENT

Anzali, Iran 2018 – 2019

Head of Operations, Freeland Event

• Led a team of over 30 to organize a freelancing event for 2,000+ attendees, enhancing industry connections and education.

Rasht, Iran 2019

Co-Organizer, Hackatourism

 Co-organized a 48-hour programming marathon for tourism innovation, managing logistics for 30 programmers across 8 teams.

LANGUAGE